hi everyone its 9:30 so let's get
大家好9:30大家好
started
开始了
welcome to modules and services my name
欢迎使用模块和服务我的名字
is Alex Buckley I work in the Java
是Alex Buckley我在Java工作
platform group at Oracle I edit the Java
Oracle的平台小组我编辑Java
language specification and the Java
语言规范和Java
Virtual Machine specification and for
虚拟机规范以及
many years now I've been working on have
我已经从事很多年了
been who have worked on the module
曾经在模块上工作过的人
system that's in JDK 9 can I do a couple
JDK 9中的系统我可以做几个
of straw polls whilst I have you all
我拥有你们所有人的时候
here who has downloaded JDK 9 please
在这里请谁下载了JDK 9
quite a few hands who is familiar with
相当多的人熟悉
Metron slash services a small number of
Metron斜杠服务数量少
hands ok who is familiar with Java util
熟悉Java util的好手
service loader some of the same hands
服务加载程序有些相同
but also different hands which is quite
但也有不同的手
interesting um who has built an
有趣的嗯，他建立了一个
application that calls service loader on
调用服务加载程序的应用程序
a small trait we're really shrinking ok
一个小特性，我们真的缩小了
so that's what this talk is about I
这就是我所说的
often say that modules are quite
经常说模块很
different than most language features
与大多数语言功能不同
such as lambdas lambdas are about the
例如lambdas lambdas是关于
shape of programs in the small
小程序的形状
individual for loops turning into method
个人为循环变成方法
calls with lambda arguments you can
可以使用lambda参数调用
reshape a program to use lambdas without
重塑程序以使用lambda
anyone noticing
有人注意到
modules are about the shape of programs
模块与程序的形状有关
in the large we deal with classes and
大体上我们处理课程
packages and get bigger from there if
包装并从那里变大
you reshape a module it's quite likely
您重塑模块很可能
that other people will notice and
别人会注意到
although modules are expressed in source
尽管模块在源代码中表示
code of the Java language they are in
他们所在的Java语言的代码
some ways outside the language they
他们在语言之外的某些方式
define architecture rather than code I
定义架构而不是代码I
say all this because services that I'll
这么说是因为我会提供的服务
be talking about here are the purest
谈论这里是最纯正的
form of architectural our construct
建筑的形式
offered by the module system there's
由模块系统提供的
something you have to design for very
你必须设计的东西
explicitly it's actually possible that
显然，实际上有可能
in your daily work you will never come
在你的日常工作中，你永远不会来
across services and all
跨服务和所有
so if you're thinking sower
所以如果你想撒种
service-oriented architectures that's
面向服务的架构
not what this is about was anyone
这不是关于任何人的事情
thinking so uh no I guess I can take
想，所以不，我想我可以接受
that line out of the presentation so now
该行不在演示文稿中，所以现在
that we're here let's talk about three
我们在这里谈论三个
things what services are in JDK nine
JDK九是什么服务
what they can do and how they can make
他们可以做什么以及如何做
old code more modular so what are
旧的代码更加模块化，所以
services and I should also check did
服务，我也应该检查
everyone see the keynotes on Monday who
每个人都在星期一看到主题演讲，
didn't see the keynote on Monday that's
星期一没有看到主题演讲
a bit unfair okay some people did it has
有点不公平，好吧，有人做到了
anyone seen any other modularity talks
任何人都看过其他模块化讨论
so good quite a few hands so that's good
很好，很多手都很好
so this is this is additive to those so
所以这是对那些的加法
you'll you'll you'll build up from there
你会你会从那里建立起来
so when we talk about modules we talk
所以当我们谈论模块时
typically talk about two things module
通常谈论两件事模块
dependencies and package exports Java
依赖项和包导出Java
desktop is the JDK module that contains
桌面是包含以下内容的JDK模块
AWT and swing as you can see it
您可以看到AWT和摆动
expresses a dependency on the java xml
表示对java xml的依赖
module for some internal implementation
一些内部实现的模块
reason so that it can access all of the
原因，以便它可以访问所有
public types in the api exported by Java
Java导出的api中的公共类型
XML and Java desktop exports the
XML和Java桌面导出
java.awt package so that anyone who
java.awt包，以便任何人
requires Java desktop can themselves
需要Java桌面自己
access the exported public types of the
访问导出的公共类型
AWT api the coupling between Java
AWT API Java之间的耦合
desktop and Java XML is very tight if
桌面和Java XML非常紧密，如果
java xml isn't found at compile time
编译时找不到Java xml
then Java desktop which requires it
然后是需要它的Java桌面
cannot be built and if java xml isn't
无法建立，如果不是Java xml
found at runtime then no system
在运行时发现，然后没有系统
depending on Java desktop can start
取决于Java桌面是否可以启动
since desktops dependency on XML is
因为台式机对XML的依赖是
unresolved
未解决
there is another kind of coupling
还有另一种耦合
between modules that is much looser than
模块之间的距离比
that it's so useful that we've built it
它是如此有用，我们已经建立了它
into the module system it involves one
进入模块系统，它涉及到一个
module requesting and implementation of
模块的请求与实现
an interface and other modules providing
接口和其他模块提供
implementations of that interface I'm
我是该接口的实现
actually going to say that again
会再说一遍
because that's what this entire
因为这就是整个
presentation is about one module
演示是关于一个模块的
requests an implementation of an
要求实施
interface other modules provide
其他模块提供的接口
implementations of that interface as an
该接口的实现
example the Java desktop module could
Java桌面模块可以
request an implementation of some print
要求实施一些印刷品
service lookup interface while another
服务查找界面，而另一个
module print Lib has some class that
模块打印库有一些类
implements print service lookup at
在以下位置实现打印服务查找
runtime code in the Java desktop module
Java桌面模块中的运行时代码
to do with printing can call a simple
做打印可以叫简单
standard API to obtain an instance of
标准API以获取
print service lookup the instance in
打印服务在以下位置查找实例
this case would be of class a fast print
这种情况将是一种快速打印
from the print Lib module but Java
从print Lib模块，但Java
desktop does not require print Lib this
桌面不需要打印Lib this
means that Java desktop can be resolved
意味着可以解决Java桌面
by the module system even if print Lib
通过模块系统即使打印库
is not present at compile time or
在编译时不存在或
runtime also print Lib would not export
运行时也打印lib不会导出
the package that contains that fast
包含那个快速包
print class fast print is a class it's
打印类快速打印是它的一个类
not an API that other modules should
不是其他模块应该使用的API
access directly other modules like Java
直接访问其他模块，例如Java
desktop should invoke methods of fast
桌面应调用快速方法
print only through the print service
仅通过打印服务打印
lookup interface what do the module
查找界面该模块做什么
declarations look like for this
声明看起来像这样
relationship it's very simple Java
关系，这是非常简单的Java
desktop would say that it uses print
桌面会说它使用打印
service lookup and the print Lib module
服务查询和Print Lib模块
would say that it provides print service
会说它提供打印服务
look up with the
用
print glass print service lookup is
印刷玻璃印刷服务查找为
called the service type the service type
称为服务类型
is usually an interface but it can be an
通常是一个接口，但可以是
abstract class or even a concrete class
抽象类甚至是具体类
if you really have a need for that fast
如果您真的需要这么快
print is the provider class the provider
print是提供者类，提供者
class must be a concrete class that
班级必须是一个具体的班级
implements or extends the service type
实现或扩展服务类型
and declares a no arts constructor so
并声明没有艺术的构造函数
that ik so that it can be instantiated
该ik，以便可以实例化
by the module system we say that Java
通过模块系统我们说Java
desktop is the consumer module he stops
桌面是他停止的消费者模块
with the dark blue arrow and print lib
带有深蓝色箭头并打印lib
is a provider module he's got the purple
是提供商模块，他有紫色
arrow notice in Java desktop that you
Java桌面中的箭头通知您
are seeing requires take a module named
看到需要带一个名为
java xml exports take a package name and
java xml导出采用包名称和
uses take a type name three different
用途取三个不同的类型名称
properties of a module three different
三种不同模块的属性
keywords three different kinds of
三种不同的关键字
arguments the provides in print Lib
在打印库中提供的参数
takes two type names one for the service
接受两个类型名称，一个用于服务
type and one for the provider class and
类型，一个用于提供程序类，
that provides directive is the modular
提供指令的是模块化
equivalent of a file called met room
等效于称为会议室的文件
slash services slash print service
斜线服务斜线打印服务
lookup that would have listed the fast
查找将列出快速
print class prior to JDK nine if a jar
如果不是jar，则在JDK之前的九个类上打印
file has a module info class compiled
文件已编译了模块信息类
from this module declaration then any
从这个模块声明然后
files in mods in Metron services are
Metron服务中的mod中的文件是
ignored the module declarations idea of
忽略了模块声明的思想
uses and provides wins
使用并提供胜利
just to clarify what's going on here
只是为了澄清这里发生的事情
there is no dependency injection here if
如果没有依赖注入
your module says uses some service type
您的模块说使用某种服务类型
and you have a field of that service
而且您有该服务的领域
type then it is not the case that an
类型，那么情况并非如此
instance of that service type is
该服务类型的实例是
magically assigned to the fields you
神奇地分配给你的领域
have to ask for an instance
不得不要求一个实例
of the service type explicitly so let's
类型的服务，所以让我们
talk about that to obtain an instance of
谈论获得一个实例
the print service lookup interface code
打印服务查找接口代码
hypothetical code in the Java desktop
Java桌面中的假设代码
module employs the service loader API
模块采用服务加载程序API
introduced in Java 6 the key method in
Java 6中引入的关键方法
service loader on the second line is
第二行的服务加载程序是
load it takes a class object java.lang
加载需要一个类对象java.lang
class representing a service type so
代表服务类型的类
print service lookup dock last as long
打印服务查找停靠站使用时间最长
as Java desktop is containing this code
因为Java桌面包含此代码
says that it uses print service lookup
说它使用打印服务查找
that load method returns a service
该加载方法返回服务
loader object capable of yielding
能够屈服的加载器对象
instances of that service type the
该服务的实例键入
module system works behind the scenes to
模块系统在幕后工作
assist service loader the module system
协助服务装载者模块系统
automatically discovers provider modules
自动发现提供者模块
at startup by scanning modules in the
在启动时，通过扫描
Java Runtime image and modular jars on
Java运行时映像和模块化jar
the module path now there could be lots
模块路径现在可能有很多
of provider modules there could be more
提供程序模块的数量可能会更多
than one provider module for print
一个供应商模块进行打印
service lookup which means more than one
服务查询意味着不止一个
provide a class that implements the
提供一个实现
interface each instance that service
接口服务的每个实例
loader yields of the service type is of
服务类型的加载程序收益为
a different provider class helpfully
不同的提供者类有帮助
service load at implements iterables so
的服务负载实现了可迭代
the P the PS L's which is the service
P是服务的PS L
loader object implement iterable so you
加载程序对象实现可迭代，因此您
can for each your way through the
可以通过每种方式
available instances known to service
已知可服务的可用实例
loader looking for the one you like
装载机寻找您喜欢的那个
in this case Java desktop hopes to find
在这种情况下，Java桌面希望找到
a print service lookup implementation
打印服务查找实现
that offers a specialist print service
提供专业的印刷服务
involving a particular dot flavor I
涉及一种特殊的点味
don't know what doc flavors are but I
不知道是什么文档风格，但我
know they're to do with print service
知道他们与打印服务有关
lookups if service loader yields no
如果服务加载程序未生成，则进行查找
instances of print service lookup
打印服务查找的实例
or if it did but for some reason none of
或是否这样做，但由于某种原因
them in the for-loop body there could
他们在for循环体内
offer the specialist service desired in
提供所需的专业服务
this case by the code then the code has
这种情况下通过代码然后代码有
to decide what to do in this case it
决定在这种情况下该怎么做
decides to return a default in service
决定返回服务中的默认值
objects now all of this code would
对象，所有这些代码将
typically live in a static method of the
通常生活在静态方法中
service type so that print service
服务类型，以便打印服务
lookup is its own factory for obtaining
查找是其自己的工厂，用于获取
implementations
实作
now before JDK 8 interfaces couldn't
现在无法使用JDK 8接口
have static methods so most service
有静态方法，所以大多数服务
types print servers lookup were abstract
打印服务器查找的类型是抽象的
classes rather than interfaces but now
类而不是接口，但现在
that interfaces can have static methods
接口可以具有静态方法
its more common for the service type
对于服务类型来说更常见
print service lookup to be an interface
将打印服务查找为接口
at this point everyone asks if service
在这一点上，每个人都问是否服务
loader finds all provider classes that
加载程序会找到所有
implements that print service lookup
实现该打印服务查找
interface and yields an instance of each
接口并产生每个的实例
one
一
how does Java desktop that contains that
Java桌面如何包含该内容
code specify that fast print is my
代码指定快速打印是我的
favorite implementation of print service
最喜欢的打印服务实现
lookup alternatively how does the print
查找或如何打印
Lib module specify that my class fast
lib模块指定我的班快
print is the best implementation of
打印是最好的实现
print service la carpa trust me the
打印服务la carpa相信我
other question everyone asks is about
每个人问的另一个问题是关于
ordering how does Java desktop the
订购Java桌面如何
consumer module specify that it prefers
消费者模块指定自己喜欢的模块
the fast print implementation of print
打印的快速打印实现
surface lookup to the net print
净打印的表面查找
implementation but that it will be happy
实施，但会很高兴
to run with net print if fast print is
如果使用快速打印，则可以使用网络打印
not present now bear in mind that
现在不存在，请记住
provider modules on the right usually
通常在右侧的提供程序模块
don't know about each other so they
彼此不认识，所以他们
cannot reasonably be involved in
无法合理地参与
selecting or sorting implementations the
选择或排序实现
consumer module Java desktop is
消费者模块Java桌面是
obviously the right place to do it
显然合适的地方
but this quickly leads to complicated
但这很快导致复杂
schemes that encode provider preferences
编码提供程序首选项的方案
in a module declaration
在模块声明中
now we're trying to keep the module
现在我们试图保留该模块
system simple so the answer is no one
系统简单，答案无人能及
specifies a global sort of static
指定静态的全局种类
preference for provider classes at least
提供者类别的偏好至少
not in a module declaration for the
不在模块声明中
consumer instead the basis for choosing
消费者代替选择的基础
one provider class over another is
一个提供者类比另一个提供者类是
application dependence it's a choice the
应用程序依赖性是一种选择
consumer module has to make by
消费者模块必须由
inspecting the properties of available
检查可用属性
provider classes when they come back
提供者类回来时
from service loader and by properties I
从服务加载程序和属性我
don't mean reflecting over their fields
并不意味着反思他们的领域
I mean calling methods of the service
我的意思是调用服务的方法
type on every instance of the discovered
在发现的每个实例上键入
provider classes so recall that Java
提供程序类，因此请回想一下Java
desktop this is code in Java desktop
桌面，这是Java桌面中的代码
calls after it's got the service loader
服务加载器调用
and it's iterating through the print
遍历整个印刷品
surface lookup implementations it calls
它调用的表面查找实现
the get default print service method on
获取默认的打印服务方法
each instance of print service look up
查找打印服务的每个实例
and then makes further calls on the
然后在
result is dot flavor supported to decide
结果是支持点式决定
if that instance is acceptable for
如果该实例可以接受
whatever java desktop is trying to do
任何Java桌面正在尝试做的事情
the consumer module should not be
使用者模块不应为
concerned with the identity of the
与身份有关
provider classes the provider classes
提供程序类提供程序类
are private details of the provider
是提供者的私人详细信息
modules in fact we strongly discourage
实际上，我们强烈建议不要使用模块
provider modules from exporting its
提供者模块导出其
provider classes because if they're
提供程序类，因为如果它们是
exported it encourages people like this
出口它鼓励这样的人
guy to code around the interface and
围绕接口编写代码的人，
directly against the class at which
直接针对哪个阶级
point you've been you've lost the
点你去过你已经失去了
benefit of loose coupling
松耦合的好处
so my advice is to think of a service
所以我的建议是考虑一项服务
type the interface for which
键入其接口
implementations will be found as a
实现将被发现为
coarse grained selector a service type
粗粒选择器服务类型
like print service lookup should offer
如打印服务查找应提供
enough descriptor methods about the
关于足够的描述符方法
quality of implementation for a consumer
消费者的实施质量
module to select the best provider class
选择最佳提供者类别的模块
in our example so far print service
在到目前为止的示例中，打印服务
lookup the service type print service
查找服务类型打印服务
lookup is actually a proxy for the real
查找实际上是真实的代理
print service objects of interest there
在那里打印感兴趣的服务对象
may be many instances of print service
可能是打印服务的许多实例
lookup on a system in different modules
在不同模块中的系统上查找
each one representing many instances of
每个代表许多实例
print service but able to offer a
打印服务，但能够提供
default print service to consumers in
消费者的默认打印服务
another scenario the service type might
服务类型可能会出现的另一种情况
directly represent an object of interest
直接代表感兴趣的对象
in this example the print service
在此示例中，打印服务
interface itself or the bottom actually
界面本身或底部
offers a rich enough set of descriptor
提供足够丰富的描述符
methods dot flavor related that it could
可能与风味相关的方法
perhaps be a legitimate service type of
也许是合法的服务类型
its own how much abstraction you design
自己设计多少抽象
into your service type depends on your
您的服务类型取决于您
application the main factor is how heavy
应用的主要因素是有多沉重
the ultimate objects of interest are for
最终的目的是为了
example if the nature of one of these
例如，如果其中之一的性质
print service things is that instantiate
打印服务的事情就是实例化
in one might be slow
可能很慢
perhaps because a provider class might
也许是因为提供程序类可能
scan the network looking for printers
扫描网络以寻找打印机
then there is value in print service
那么印刷服务就有价值
lookup instances to act as proxies that
查找实例充当代理
decide whether a print service instance
决定是否打印服务实例
is actually available but if the nature
实际可用，但如果自然
of a print service is that it's cheap
打印服务的一个特点是它很便宜
and easy to instantiate then the value
并易于实例化然后值
of print service lookup as the the proxy
打印服务查找作为代理
service type is diminished I hope it's
服务类型减少了，我希望它是
clear this is nothing to do with the
清除这与
services are nothing to do with print
服务与印刷无关
services services are a completely
服务服务是完全
general mechanism but to exemplify them
一般机制，但以例证为例
I have to get a concrete service to a
我必须为
particular service type and
特定的服务类型和
a small set of provider classes and then
一小组提供程序类，然后
the question is is great I've got
这个问题很好，我有
multiple provider classes what do I do
多个提供程序类我该怎么办
of course the other question is what if
当然，另一个问题是
I have no provider classes what do I do
我没有提供者课程，我该怎么办
we'll come on to that it's interesting
我们将继续讲，这很有趣
to look at the service types the
查看服务类型
interfaces consumed by Java desktop the
Java桌面消耗的接口
service types in blue are proxies or
蓝色的服务类型是代理或
factories or wrappers if you prefer
工厂或包装，如果你喜欢
print service lookup is among them there
打印服务查找在其中
is e there is in the middle print
中间有印刷吗
service lookup the type next to it
服务查找旁边的类型
stream print service factory is the same
流打印服务工厂是相同的
deal and looking from the top you would
交易，并从顶部看你会
call methods on instances of input
输入实例上的调用方法
method descriptor in order to find the
方法描述符以便找到
one that offers the desired input method
提供所需输入法的一种
capital i capital m and you would call
首都我首都m，你会打电话
methods on instances of image input
图像输入实例的方法
stream spi service provider interface to
流SPI服务提供商接口
choose one that can best convert your
选择一种最能转换您的
data into an image input stream the
数据进入图像输入流
Javadoc for those five SPI types sort of
这五种SPI类型的Javadoc
near the top even says the intent is
靠近顶部甚至说意图是
that it be relatively inexpensive to
相对便宜
load and inspect all available service
加载并检查所有可用服务
provider classes ie implementations of
提供程序类，即
image input stream SPI those classes may
图像输入流SPI这些类可能
then be used to locate and instantiate
然后用于定位和实例化
more heavyweight classes that will
更多重量级的课程
perform actual work in this case
在这种情况下执行实际工作
instances of image reader image writer
图像读取器的实例图像写入器
image transcoder image input stream and
图像代码转换器图像输入流和
image output stream the service types in
图像输出流中的服务类型
Brown are not proxies or factories but
布朗不是代理人或工厂，而是
rather they represent the actual objects
而是它们代表实际的对象
of interest
出于兴趣
so while MIDI device provider sort of in
因此，虽然MIDI设备提供商
the middle in blue is just a proxy for
蓝色的中间只是代表
obtaining MIDI device objects MIDI file
获取MIDI设备对象MIDI文件
reader just below it in Brown is real
布朗下面的读者是真实的
business logic a provider class for MIDI
业务逻辑MIDI的提供程序类
file reader
文件阅读器
knows how to obtain actually a MIDI
知道如何实际获取MIDI
sequence from a file the bottom line is
文件的顺序最底线是
that the service load API and the module
服务加载API和模块
system are agnostic about the
系统对
granularity in design of your service
服务设计的粒度
type which means that details like
类型，表示类似
quality of implementation issues are
实施质量问题是
kept out of the module declarations now
现在不包含在模块声明中
you may be wondering where are the
您可能想知道在哪里
service types the print service lookup
服务类型打印服务查找
interface actually live a service type
界面实际上是服务类型
is just an interface in a package in a
只是一个包中的接口
module that package will almost always
该模块几乎总是
be exported from the module all those
从模块中导出所有这些
green arrows so that other modules such
绿色箭头，这样其他模块
as Java desktop is a consumer and print
因为Java桌面是消费者和印刷品
nib as a provider can require the the
笔尖作为提供者可以要求
service types module and access the
服务类型模块并访问
service type a consumer module like Java
服务类型诸如Java之类的使用者模块
desktop needs to access the service type
桌面需要访问服务类型
for its users directive the dark blue
为用户指示深蓝色
arrows and for the code that employees
箭头和用于员工的代码
service loader
服务加载器
to get instances of the service type in
获取服务类型的实例
other words the print service lookup
换句话说，打印服务查找
type name is actually in the code of
类型名称实际上在
Java desktop so there's a real access
Java桌面，因此可以真正访问
across modules there a provider module
跨模块有提供者模块
like print neural-net prints needs to
像打印神经网络打印需要
access the service type for its provides
访问其提供的服务类型
directive and of course for the class
指令，当然是针对班级的
fast print or net print that actually
实际的快速打印或净打印
implements or extends the service type
实现或扩展服务类型
in general there can be many consumer
通常会有很多消费者
modules on the left and many provider
左侧的模块和许多提供商
modules on the right for a given service
特定服务右侧的模块
type a consumer module will say requires
输入使用者模块会说需要
and uses while a provider module will
并在提供商模块将使用时使用
say requires and provides the arrows
说出要求并提供箭头
looked complicated when they're all
他们都看起来很复杂
drawn out but but browsing the source of
引出，但浏览的来源
module declarations
模块声明
requires users requires provides makes
需要用户需要提供品牌
it pretty clear what the module
很清楚什么模块
relationships are and by the way this
关系是这样的
was this has this to some extent is
在某种程度上有这个吗
irreducible even if you were doing a
即使你在做一个
service loader prior to nine this is
9之前的服务加载程序是
what was really going on these are the
这些到底是怎么回事
essential relationships between the
之间的基本关系
consumers and the providers the good
消费者和提供者的好处
news is if you skim for example the JDK
新闻是如果您浏览了例如JDK
module summary or even the Javadoc
模块摘要甚至Javadoc
produced from your own modules it's very
由您自己的模块产生的
easy to see which modules are consumers
容易看到哪些模块是消费者
and of what and which modules are
以及什么和哪些模块
providers and of what and that's
提供者，以及那是什么
definitely in an advanced over grapping
绝对处于高级过度
for service loaded load calls and
用于服务加载的调用和
wondering which jars on the classpath
想知道在类路径上的罐子
have files in Metron services all that
在Metron服务中拥有所有文件
said it's not man dat tree for a service
说不是服务员
type to be defined in a different module
要在其他模块中定义的类型
than the consumers and providers in the
比消费者和提供者
JDK it's common for a module which
JDK是常见的模块
defines and exports a service type to
定义服务类型并将其导出到
also be a consumer module for that
也是为此的消费者模块
service type for example the Java
服务类型，例如Java
desktop module exports the java.awt mSpy
桌面模块导出java.awt mSpy
package at the top so that other modules
包装在顶部，以便其他模块
can implement the spi types and act as
可以实现spi类型并充当
provider modules and Java desktop uses
提供程序模块和Java桌面使用
at the top on the right java.awt mSpy
在右侧java.awt mSpy的顶部
input method descriptor so the code in
输入法描述符，因此代码在
java desktop can use service loader to
Java桌面可以使用服务加载程序
get instances of that service type many
获得该服务类型的实例很多
well-known frameworks in the JDK such as
JDK中的知名框架，例如
logging file system and date/time
记录文件系统和日期/时间
support this kind of customization via
通过支持这种定制
provider modules
提供者模块
it's also relatively common in the JDK
在JDK中也相对常见
for a consumer module to also be a
消费者模块也可以
provider module for example Java desktop
提供程序模块，例如Java桌面
uses print service lookup really does
使用打印服务查找确实可以
and also it provides an implementation
并且它提供了一个实现
in the form of Sun print print servers
以Sun打印服务器的形式
lookup provider this allows the code in
查找提供程序，这允许在
Java desktop that returns print services
返回打印服务的Java桌面
to be assured that it can always return
可以保证它总是可以返回
at least some instance of a default
至少有一些默认情况
provider class some print print service
提供程序类一些打印打印服务
lookup provider ultimately you can see
查找提供商最终您可以看到
that a single module like Java desktop
像Java桌面这样的单个模块
may contain the service type and the
可能包含服务类型和
user's directive to help the code
用户指令以帮助代码
employing service loader and provides
雇用服务加载者并提供
directives to specify one or more
指定一个或多个的指令
provider classes so that's what services
提供程序类，这就是服务
are service relationships uses and
服务关系的使用和
provides our a first-class thing in the
提供我们一流的东西
module system programming against
针对模块系统编程
service types being a consumer module
服务类型是使用者模块
allows the provider modules and the
允许提供者模块和
provider classes to be strongly
提供者类要坚决
encapsulated and many JDK frameworks use
封装并且许多JDK框架都在使用
services I shouldn't say use cause uses
服务我不应该说使用原因使用
ism keyword build on services rely on
ism关键字依赖于服务
services and are customized with them
服务并根据他们进行定制
so moving on how to use services for a
所以继续介绍如何使用服务
particular use case
特定用例
it should be obvious that services let
很明显，服务让
you plug in implementations that weren't
您插入的不是
known to your program at compile time
程序在编译时已知
they are discovered dynamically via
通过以下方式动态发现它们
service loader for examples that show
服务加载器的示例说明
this I recommend the Java 9 modularity
我推荐Java 9模块化
book that's out this week it's not so
这本书本周不是
obvious that services are actually the
很明显，服务实际上是
key to encoding a number of
编码多个
sophisticated relationships between
之间的复杂关系
modules that might otherwise appear to
否则可能会出现的模块
be unsupported by the module system in
不受模块系统的支持
particular I'm going to talk about how
特别是我要讲的是
optional module dependencies are neatly
可选模块依赖关系整齐
encoded with services as an example
以服务编码为例
consider the Java scripting module in
考虑一下Java脚本模块
the JDK it offers an API to evaluate
JDK提供了一个评估API
snippets of code the details of that API
代码片段详细介绍了该API
don't matter there is some some class
没关系，有一些课
eval that evaluates snippets of code now
评估现在评估代码段的评估
at runtime there might be many
在运行时可能有很多
implementations of scripting languages
脚本语言的实现
capable of evaluating snippets such as
能够评估例如
NASA horn that's Oracle's implementation
NASA号角是Oracle的实现
of JavaScript or groovy or JRuby etc how
JavaScript或groovy或JRuby等如何
is the Java scripting module meant to
是Java脚本模块的意思是
depend on them it seems like it seems
依靠他们似乎
like we need a way to say in the module
就像我们需要一种在模块中说的方式
declaration for Java scripting requires
Java脚本声明需要
optional module name so that Java
可选模块名称，以便Java
scripting would read whichever modules
脚本将读取任何模块
are available and if none are available
可用，如果没有可用
that would be okay the module system
没关系，模块系统
would still start even though some of
即使某些
the required things might not be present
所需的内容可能不存在
the trouble with requires optional is
需要可选的麻烦是
that it would only make sense when the
只有当
Java when the Java scripting module has
Java脚本模块具有Java时
already been built but suppose you're at
已经建成，但假设您在
compile time
编译时间
what if source in the Java scripting
如果Java脚本中的源代码怎么办
module refers to a class in one of the
模块指的是其中一个
optional modules either JDK scripting a
可选模块，要么是JDK脚本，要么是
Sehorne or groovy script engine and that
Sehorne或groovy脚本引擎等等
optional module isn't present at compile
可选模块在编译时不存在
time it's not acceptable for a Java
时间对于Java来说是不可接受的
compiler to proceed when it can't find
编译器在找不到时继续执行
classes referenced in source code nor do
源代码中引用的类也不
we want to relax the java language with
我们想放松Java语言
some form of loose dynamic typing that
某种形式的宽松动态类型
says well I see there's a reference to
说很好，我看到有一个参考
some type from an optional module and
来自可选模块的某些类型，以及
it's not here at compile time but it
它不是在编译时在这里，而是
might be here at runtime so I'll just
可能在运行时在这里，所以我只是
compile it and hope that the types will
编译它，并希望类型会
work out that's not really the java way
弄清楚这不是真的Java方法
now you can get a bit further if you
现在，如果您能更进一步
would in your source code never refer
在您的源代码中永远不会引用
directly to class names from the
直接从
optional modules and instead access them
可选模块，而是访问它们
via reflection but that's a very painful
通过反射，但这是非常痛苦的
programming style it's how you had to
编程风格，这是您必须要做的
code on the Java ME platform when
Java ME平台上的代码
different devices implemented different
不同的设备实现了不同的
API s and you had to dynamically
API，您必须动态地
discover what was there and code it
发现那里的东西并编码
through the reflection API it just
通过反射API
doesn't scale this is a slide you will
不按比例缩放这是一张幻灯片
want to take a picture of the proper way
想以适当的方式拍照
to program against zero one or many
针对零个或多个编程
modules is with services services
模块与服务一起
introduce a level of indirection by
通过引入一个间接级别
means of the service type you can
您可以使用的服务类型
mechanically translate an optional
机械翻译可选
module dependency at the top I should
我应该在顶部模块依赖
say sort of a hypothetical optional
说一种假设的可选
dependency you can't write requires
你不能写的依赖要求
optional right it's a hypothetical thing
可选权，这是假设的事情
but if you want to write that you you
但是如果你想写你自己
can translate it to a pair of non
可以翻译成一对非
optional dependencies on the module
模块上的可选依赖项
which exports the service type there's a
导出服务类型有一个
consumer module Java scripting which is
消费者模块Java脚本是
going to use the service type and their
将使用服务类型及其
various provider modules on the right
右侧的各种提供程序模块
that require the service type module
需要服务类型模块
tutor so they can implement script
导师，以便他们可以执行脚本
engine Factory and they declare that
引擎工厂，他们宣布
they provide implementation
他们提供实施
this scheme at the bottom decouples the
底部的这个方案解耦了
number and the identity of the provider
提供商的编号和身份
modules on the right from the consumer
正确的消费者模块
module which is what optionality is all
模块是什么，全部是可选项
about I recognize this is an abstract
关于我认识到这是一个抽象
picture the benefit is it fits on one
图片的好处是它适合一个
slide does this make sense
幻灯片有意义吗
it's very hard to tell up here whether
在这里很难说出是否
this programming idiom that we've burned
我们烧掉的这个编程习惯
into the java language with these
这些变成Java语言
keywords uses and provides which is
关键字使用并提供了
clearly more about the architecture of
更清楚地了解
the relationship between different
不同之间的关系
modules it's sort of the opposite of of
模块，它与
lambdas in their individual expressions
Lambda在其个人表达中
in method bodies it's very hard to tell
在方法主体中很难分辨
how well it comes across but really this
效果如何，但实际上
is the essence of modularity it's about
是关于模块化的本质
making the consumer modules not care who
使消费者模块不在乎谁
the provider modules are modularity is
提供者模块是模块化的
basically about not caring and services
基本上是关于不关心和服务
or how you do that you just rely on a
或您只是依靠
well-designed service type and you let
精心设计的服务类型，您让
the module system find the providers so
模块系统找到提供者，因此
since Java scripting is a JDK module it
由于Java脚本是JDK模块，因此
will not come as a surprise that it's
不会感到惊讶的是
not only the consumer module that says
不仅消费者模块说
uses but actually also where the service
用途，但实际上也在哪里
type lives so at the top the Java
类型生活在Java的顶部
scripting module it both uses the script
脚本模块，它们都使用脚本
engine factory interface because there's
引擎工厂界面，因为
code in Java scripting that call service
调用服务的Java脚本中的代码
loader and Java scripting actually is
加载器和Java脚本实际上是
where that interface lives so it exports
该接口所在的位置，因此可以导出
it for everyone else to implement then
然后让其他人实施
further down the NASS horn and groovy
深入NASS的号角
modules again all hypothetical there
那里的模块又都是假想的
isn't actually groovy module called that
实际上不是俗称的模块
but I've got to have some example they
但我必须举一些例子
each provide their implementation of
各自提供其实现
script engine Factory and the module
脚本引擎工厂和模块
system discovers the role of these two
系统发现这两个角色
modules as provider modules
模块作为提供程序模块
when the system starts up assuming that
当系统启动时假设
jars for these two modules are on the
这两个模块的罐子放在
module path now code in Java scripting
现在，Java脚本中的模块路径代码
and you'll find my pointer code and Java
然后您会找到我的指针代码和Java
scripting can employ service loader to
脚本编写可以使用服务加载程序
get instances of script engine factory
获取脚本引擎工厂的实例
and call its methods without worrying
并调用其方法而不必担心
where the implementations come from the
实施来自
script engine factory interface has many
脚本引擎工厂界面有很多
descriptor methods to let provider
描述符方法让提供者
classes encode the quality of
类编码的质量
implementation of the script engines
脚本引擎的实现
they ultimately offer I'm not going to
他们最终提出，我不会
show script engine factory because it
显示脚本引擎工厂，因为它
would be a big long list of get methods
将是一大堆get方法
it's pretty easy to look up and you'll
查找起来很容易，您会
see a sort of get get the name of the
看到一种获取获取名称
script engine and get some details of
脚本引擎并获取一些详细信息
what it some of the language features
它的一些语言功能
that it supports you will notice the
它支持您，您会注意到
Java scripting module does not say it
Java脚本模块不说
requires JavaScript jdk scripting nass
需要JavaScript jdk脚本nass
horn or groovy script engine in fact if
角或常规脚本引擎实际上是否
you look closely you'll see that those
你仔细看，你会发现
modules require Java scripting where the
模块需要Java脚本，其中
service type lives so in effect the way
服务类型的生存方式
you get optional dependencies with very
你会得到非常可选的依赖
loose coupling is by inverting them
松耦合是通过反转它们
rather than a high level scripting API
而不是高级脚本API
module requiring lower level
需要较低级别的模块
implementation modules everyone looks up
每个人都在看的实现模块
by requiring the module with the service
通过要求模块与服务
type so service relationships encode
类型，以便服务关系编码
optional module dependencies that means
可选模块依赖关系
that services are not just giving loose
服务不只是松散
coupling as a sort of a mechanism in the
耦合作为一种机制
module system but actually a better
模块系统，但实际上更好
separation of concerns between the
之间的关注点分离
interface and the implementations and
接口和实现，以及
services are almost always a better
服务几乎总是更好
choice for discovering implementations
选择实现的选择
than messing around with reflection
而不是倒影
class dot for name and the like
名称等的类点
so nearly done let's talk about cycles
差不多完成了，让我们来谈谈周期
this is a graph of some of the modules
这是一些模块的图形
in JDK 9 what do you notice about it it
在JDK 9中，您对此有何注意
is a cyclic there are no cycles there
是循环的，那里没有循环
are no loops it is a directed acyclic
没有循环，它是有向非循环的
graph the module system does not allow
图形模块系统不允许
cycles in your requires directives it
在您的require指令中循环
has taken almost a decade to detangle
花费了将近十年的时间
the tens of thousands of classes in the
数以万计的课程
JDK to the acyclic and relatively sane
JDK到无环且相对理智
States you see here we'd like to keep it
您在这里看到的州我们希望保留它
that way
那样
in fact one of the motivations for
实际上是
investing in modular ization of a code
投资代码的模块化
base is the knowledge that once complete
基础是一旦完成的知识
there won't be any backsliding into the
不会有任何退路
ball of mud that cyclic dependencies
循环依赖的泥球
allow and we're not the only ones who
允许，我们不是唯一的
think like this java application
像这样的java应用程序思考
architecture from 2012 is an outstanding
2012年的建筑是杰出的
book about modularity in a section
在一节中有关模块化的书
entitled you actually couldn't make this
有资格的你实际上无法做到这一点
up it's true cyclic dependence is the
真正的周期性依赖是
death knell
丧钟
it says excessive dependencies are bad
它说过多的依赖是不好的
excessive requires basically are bad but
过多的需求基本上是不好的，但是
cyclic dependencies are especially bad
循环依赖特别糟糕
it goes on to say generally speaking
一般说来
cycles are always bad however sometimes
周期总是不好，但有时
some cycles are worse than others cycles
有些周期比其他周期更糟糕
among classes are tolerable assuming
类之间是可以容忍的
they don't cause cycles among the
它们不会导致
packages or modules containing them
包含它们的软件包或模块
cycles among packages may also be
包之间的周期也可能是
tolerable assuming they don't cause
假设它们不会导致
cycles among the modules containing them
在包含它们的模块之间循环
module relationships must never be
模块关系绝不能
cyclic however in real life there are
周期性的，但是在现实生活中
sometimes cycles which seem inevitable
有时周期似乎不可避免
let's look at a real life example
让我们看一个真实的例子
let's assume there is a logging project
假设有一个日志记录项目
that consists of two modules logging API
由两个模块记录API组成
and logging in pull one requiring the
并登录需要一个拉
other so that the logging API module
其他，以便日志记录API模块
requires the logging implementation
需要记录实现
module that's the blue arrow why well
模块就是蓝色箭头，为什么
maybe a static method in the API module
API模块中的静态方法
has been traditionally using reflection
传统上一直使用反射
to create instances of the locking
创建锁定实例
implementation now let's assume there is
现在我们假设存在
some HTTP client module in an unrelated
不相关的一些HTTP客户端模块
project it wants to log HTTP requests so
它想要记录HTTP请求的项目
it starts to require another blue arrow
它开始需要另一个蓝色箭头
the logging API module there are no
日志API模块没有
services yet it's it's just too requires
服务，但这只是需要
and finally let's assume that the
最后让我们假设
logging implementation module wants to
日志记录实现模块想要
add a feature where it can upload logs
添加可以上传日志的功能
to a web server at this point the author
在这一点上作者
of logging in pull is out of luck in JDK
在JDK中登录pull的过程很不幸
9 because for logging imple to depend on
9因为日志记录依赖
HTTP client via are requires the third
HTTP客户端通过are需要第三个
blue arrow would would create a cycle
蓝色箭头将创建一个周期
and worse it would create a cycle across
更糟糕的是，这将造成一个循环
projects that's a very uncomfortable
项目是非常不舒服的
level of coupling to manage for the rest
其余管理的耦合级别
of time what can the author of logging
时间的日志作者可以做什么
in pull do to upload logs to a web
在拉做上传日志到网络
server well one option is to find
服务器好一种选择是找到
another project that offers an HTTP
提供HTTP的另一个项目
client module but that seems like
客户端模块，但看起来像
cheating another option is to email the
作弊的另一种选择是通过电子邮件发送
author of the HTTP client module and ask
HTTP客户端模块的作者并询问
them to stop requiring logging API but
他们停止要求记录API，但是
now the author of HTTP client is the
现在，HTTP客户端的作者是
person in the position of find another
可以找到另一个人的人
project even if the author of HTTP
项目，即使HTTP的作者
client is willing to use a different
客户愿意使用其他
logging
测井
the author of logging imple would still
日志实现的作者仍然会
have to wait for a new release of HTTP
必须等待新版本的HTTP
clients that did so who is at fault here
这样做的客户谁在这里错
it's not the logging in pull module who
不是拉入模块登录
is just trying to reuse remember in the
只是想重用记得在
keynote Mark said a module is a set of
主题演讲Mark说一个模块是一组
packages designed for reuse the logging
为重用日志而设计的软件包
imple module is just trying to reuse the
imple模块只是试图重用
logically independence HTTP client
逻辑上独立的HTTP客户端
module and I don't think the problem
模块，我不认为这个问题
lies with the HTTP client module who is
在于HTTP客户端模块
just trying to reuse a public logging
只是试图重用公共日志
API the fault lies with the logging API
API错误在于日志记录API
module it is poor style for an API to
模块，API的样式很差
rely to require its implementation for
依靠要求其实现
two reasons
两个原因
first it means implementation details
首先，它意味着实施细节
are likely to leak into the API which
可能会泄漏到API中
makes the API less understandable second
使API难以理解
it means that exercising the API needs
这意味着要满足API的需求
the entire implementation to be up and
整个实施需要
running which makes the API less
运行使API减少
testable plus given everything I've said
加上我所说的一切
so far it's kind of obviously wrong
到目前为止，这显然是错误的
consider the Java base module it
考虑一下Java基本模块吧
declares the Java util collection
声明Java util集合
interface but it will be stupid for the
介面，但对于
Java base module to depend on to require
Java基本模块依赖于要求
any module that implements that
任何实现该功能的模块
interface implementations depend on
接口实现取决于
interfaces not the other way around so
接口不是相反
the best outcome is for logging in pull
最好的结果是登录拉
to depend on logging API rather than the
依赖于日志记录API而不是
other way around implementations
实现的其他方式
dependent interfaces but then I hear you
依赖的接口，但是我听到了
ask how does the static method in the
请问静态方法在
API create instances of the logging
API创建日志记录实例
implementation of course with services
实施带有服务的课程
here's what the logging project should
这是日志记录项目应具有的功能
do
做
first the logging API module defines a
首先，日志API模块定义了一个
service type logger in some package and
某些程序包中的服务类型记录器，以及
that package is exported widely the
该包装广泛出口
Green Arrow's exported consumers
绿箭的出口消费者
exported to providers second the logging
导出到提供者第二次日志记录
implement the comes a provider module
实现自带的提供程序模块
it requires logging API that's the blue
它需要蓝色的日志记录API
arrow and provides an implementation of
箭头，并提供的实现
the service type the purple arrow
服务键入紫色箭头
note that the logging implementation
请注意，日志记录实现
module does not export anything finally
模块最终不会导出任何内容
the logging API module with the service
带有服务的日志记录API模块
type acts as its own consumer it says
它说类型充当其自己的消费者
that it uses the logger service type and
它使用记录器服务类型，并且
then at runtime it asks service loader
然后在运行时询问服务加载器
for an instance of logger this instance
对于记录器实例，此实例
would then be returned up to the HTTP
然后将返回到HTTP
client module which has no idea of the
客户端模块，不知道
relationship between logging api and
记录api和
locking implementation it occurs to me I
锁定实现发生在我身上
should have deleted the big blue arrow
应该删除了蓝色的大箭头
from logging in pull up to HTTP clients
从登录下拉到HTTP客户端
it should be gone pretend it's not there
它应该假装不存在
I know you're all pretending it's not
我知道你们都装作不是
there right now the HTTP client is
现在，HTTP客户端是
forced to code strictly to the logger
被迫严格记录到记录器
interface with no access to the
界面，无法访问
underlying implementation class because
基础实现类，因为
it wasn't exported from logging in pull
它不是从登录拉中导出的
the great trick basically is that
基本上，最大的技巧是
service loader act on behalf of logging
服务加载程序代表日志记录
API to look down into locking imple
查看锁定实现的API
without logging in pull so without
没有登录拉所以没有
logging API
记录API
requiring logging in pull and without
需要登录拉和没有
logging imple exporting anything to
日志记录实现将任何内容导出到
logging api in other words there is very
换句话说，记录api非常
loose coupling between the api and the
api和
implementation so it's easy to switch
实施，因此很容易切换
out logging in pull for a different
退出登录拉不同
implementation at runtime and again the
在运行时实施
HTTP client module would be unaware of
HTTP客户端模块将不知道
this happening
这件事
I need to speed up if you've get the
如果您有需要，我需要加快速度
feeling you've seen this before it's
感觉你已经看过了
because you have ten minutes ten minutes
因为你有十分钟十分钟
ago I said the way you get optional
之前我说过你选择的方式
dependencies is by inverting them rather
依赖关系是通过反转它们
than the high level scripting module
比高级脚本模块
requiring low level implementation
需要低级实施
modules everyone looks up by requiring
每个人都通过要求查找模块
the module with the service type
具有服务类型的模块
services play the same trick to break a
服务发挥相同的技巧来打破
cyclic dependency rather than the high
周期性依赖而不是高
level API module requiring the low level
需要低级别的级别API模块
implementation modules the
实施模块
implementation modules look up by
实现模块按以下方式查找
requiring the API module developing
需要开发API模块
services takes work but the payoff is
服务需要工作，但回报是
that services bring out the structure of
服务带出了
the whole program more clearly than
整个程序比
anything we've ever introduced into the
我们曾经介绍过的所有内容
Java language and since our number one
Java语言，因为我们排名第一
belief for Java code is that reading is
Java代码的信念是阅读是
more important than writing we think
比我们认为的写作更重要
that services pull their weight and
服务可以减轻他们的负担，
deserve to be widely adopted
值得广泛采用
so cycles hurt program understanding and
因此周期会损害程序理解力，
maintenance service relationships are a
维护服务关系是
natural way to break cycles and really
打破循环的自然方法
in just a few uses and provides and
仅用于几种用途，并提供和
service loader calls you can express an
服务加载程序调用，您可以表示
awful lot of application architecture so
很多应用程序架构
service is a first-class they literally
他们从字面上看是一流的服务
give you looser coupling but logically
给您宽松的耦合，但合乎逻辑
better separation of concerns and it's
更好地分离关注点，
all about the architecture rather than
所有关于架构而不是
the code jdk nine is here please
代码JDK九在这里
download it if you haven't if you want
如果没有，请下载
to know more about the module system
进一步了解模块系统
there's a number of JDK enhancement
有很多JDK增强功能
proposals jep's especially jet 261
建议捷豹特别喷气261
basically every question that you're
基本上，您所遇到的每个问题
going to ask is answered in jet 261 and
261回答了要问的问题，
with that thank you very much
非常感谢你
you
您